Welcome to the Gentamycin
pediatric dilution preparation.
We will be making a standard 2
milligram per one ML PD
Gentamycin dilution.
The compounder has performed
hand hygiene and garbing
procedures that you learned in
an earlier chapter.
Calculations have been performed
and verified by the pharmacist.
All supply items used to prepare
the pediatric dilution have been
cleaned with 70% sterile IPA
before introducing into the
outer 6 inches of the primary
engineering control.
Placement of the supply items on
the DCA will help you with the
steps for this PD dilution.
We have an empty evacuated
container vial preservative free
normal saline vial, a stock vile
preservative free gentamicin 20
milligram per two ML sterile IPA
swabs, syringes, regular needles
and sterile caps.
Make sure that all of the items
that are placed in the DCA will
receive continuous airflow from
the HEPA filter.
The compounder will open a
sterile IPA swab and place it on
the work surface for the needle
cap.
Remove the cap of the EEC vial.
Open a new sterile IPA swab.
Clean the septum of the vial.
Remove the cap of the
preservative free normal saline.
Open a new sterile IPA swab and
clean the septum of that vial.
Remove the cap to the
gentamicin.
Open a new sterile IPA swab and
clean the septum of that vial.
We will peel back the outer
packaging to the syringe,
ensuring that the critical site
will stay in first air Flammat
HEPA filter.
We'll open the needle, pulling
back the packaging.
Attach the needle, activate our
syringe so the plunger isn't so
stiff and we're going to pull
back the volume magentamycin in
this case 2 milliliters.
We'll take the cap off, put it
on that IPA pad, bevel up.
We want to be in a dark
position, go into the vial, we
will invert the vial and we'll
begin our milking method.
The needle tip needs to be in
liquid.
We're going to push with the
thumb on that flat knob, and
your forefinger and middle
finger are going to be on the
syringe.
Now we're going to troubleshoot
the air.
We're going to tap our syringe,
look for more bubbles, tap, Then
we're going to bring our needle
back in the liquid and we're
going to push that air and all
the air that is in the hub and
the lumen, we're going to change
our hand position and we're
going to pull the volume of
Argentamycin 2 milliliters.
We're going to come out of our
vial.
We're going to tap, slide and
cap our needle.
And we're going to prepare for
the pharmacist check.
We're going to open our syringe.
We're going to peel back the
packaging.
We have the tip in the airflow.
We're going to open the
packaging to our needle and
connect to our syringe.
We're going to activate this
syringe and pull back the volume
for a preservative free normal
saline, in this case 8
milliliters.
We'll get into a dart, take the
cap off, put it on that sterile
IPA pad.
We want to be bevel up with our
needle.
We're in a dart position to be
towed to 12 and six, invert the
vial and get into the position
so we can perform the milking
method.
Notice that that needle tip is
in liquid.
All the critical sites are
getting first air from the HEPA
filter, and we're going to
troubleshoot any bubles that we
have in the syringe.
I like to wait until I have a
little bit of air left.
Bring the needle all the way
into the vial.
We'll use the table top or you
can hit the side of the syringe,
bring the needle tip back into
liquid and push the rest of that
air.
And then we'll change your hand
position and we'll make sure
that we have that volume at
diluent, in this case, 8
milliliters of our preservative
free normal saline.
We'll come out of our vial and
then we'll tap slide and snap.
We'll get the volume of that
preservative free normal saline.
The pharmacist will check the
volume of that preservative free
gentamicin and then we'll
prepare to go into that empty
evacuated container vial.
We'll get into a dart, we'll
take the cap off and put it on
that sterile IPA swab, bevel up.
We're in a dark position.
We'll tippy toe to 12:00 and
6:00.
We'll go into the vial and now
we're going to use the flaps on
the syringe and we're going to
push with our thumb on the flat
knob.
And then we want to take our
thumb and we want to pull back
air to the two MLS and then
we'll come up and out of our
vial.
We do have a little liquid that
was from the hub and Lumen.
Now for new compounders, we will
open a new sterile IPA prep pad
and a new sterile IPA swab and
clean off the port of our vial.
And we're changing needles.
When changing needles, needles
first, we'll bring that needle
out of the packaging, the
critical site in the air flow,
and we're going to change
needles.
The reason we're changing
needles is that we don't have a
lot of room in this empty
evacuated container.
We're going to pull back some
air.
Remember, we don't have anything
in this hub and lumen.
It's just the 8 milliliters of
our preservatory, normal saline.
We'll take our cap off.
We're in a dark position.
Bevel up, We'll tippy toe to
12:00 and 6:00 and we will use
the flaps on the syringe and
we're now going to help that air
and we're going to milk upside
down.
We're going to push that flat
knob with our thumb and the air
is going to push all of the
liquid, ensuring that the liquid
will go through that hub and
lumen of the needle.
And then you'll bring your thumb
and you'll pull back to the
Volume 8 MLS and come up and out
of the vial.
We'll take a new sterile IPA
swab and get our syringe and our
needle.
Anytime you come out of the
hood, you're going to spray with
sterile Isopropyl alcohol on
your gloves.
We'll open a new sterile IPA
swab and we'll clean the port.
Every time we go into the vial,
we'll get our syringe for our
patient dose.
We'll open the outer packaging
of our needle.
We'll attach to our syringe.
We'll activate the plunger.
Now we don't need to have any
air.
We did a good job with our
venting.
We're going to take our cap off,
put it on our sterile IPA swab.
We're bevel up.
We're in a dark position.
We'll tippy toe to 12:00 and
6:00.
We'll invert the vial and now we
can hold our hand position and
pull liquid.
I like to troubleshoot right
away.
Tap the syringe, then bring the
needle in liquid and we'll push
the air that's in the hub in the
lumen and then we'll pull the
volume for our patient dose.
Notice all the critical sites
are getting first air from the
HEPA, then we'll hold on to the
barrel.
We'll come out of the vial,
we'll tap, slide and snap and we
have our patient dose.
We're going to prepare to cap
our syringe.
We're going to bring the sterile
caps into the direct compounding
area and we're going to open and
expose the first two caps and
then we can pick up our syringe,
get into a dart, take our needle
off, and then you'll firmly
press into the cap.